Daniel Stuart, Web Developer

■ stuheadz@gmail.com □ (860)977-2982 ■ https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielstuart-5520231a1 ♀ https://github.com/Discode-Stu

SUMMARY

My passion for web development is fueled by the satisfaction of learning something new through solving problems. I aim to create clean, powerful functions and always try to keep it simple. As a person who loves to be challenged, I look forward to applying my diverse experiences to new projects and endeavors.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Software Engineeer - Web and Mobile Multitude Insights, Inc.

August 2022 - January 2024, Cambridge, Ma

- · As a Frontend Software Engineer at Multitude Insights, I successfully transformed design concepts into interactive web applications using the Next.js javascript framework and RTK Query for efficient API state management. My responsibilities included coding responsive user interfaces, implementing complex features, and actively contributing to the planning of future features. This experience honed my ability to manage projects independently and deliver visually appealing, functional solutions within tight deadlines.
- · Within 6 months at Multitude Insights, we hired a mobile development team to create a mobile app for our project. They ended up falling short on key features, so we let them go. Recognizing the opportunity, I volunteered to take over the project. After addressing many bugs, and completing the remaining features, I successfully brought the app to market, launching it on Google Play Store (Android) and App Store (iOS).

Full Stack Engineer

Couchtour.tv December 2021 - Present

• After leaving Empirically Dev, the Couchtour.tv team wanted to keep me as I was a valuable asset to their team. I quickly learned how to code in Node.js and create AWS lambda functions to keep up with the project's backend needs

Exterior Firefighter

Williamsburg Fire Department

July 2021 - Present, Williamsburg, MA

· As a software developer, many hours are spent in front of a computer screen with little human interaction. To create balance in my life, I decided to join the volunteer fire department here in Williamsburg. Saving people's lives and helping my community in any way I can has quickly become a way of life.

Lead Frontend Developer

EmpiricallyDev

October 2020 - December 2021

- · My first software development team consisted of myself and one other individual. I learned quickly how to manage projects with overlapping deadlines and to meet the competing needs from clients.
- · We delivered three main projects an online pharmacy, an online vaccination clinic, and an online concert streaming service.
- · For the concert streaming service, I created the backend using GraphQL, AWS Appsync, and DynamoDB, along with all the frontend code utilizing ReactJS and SCSS
- · Enhanced an existing ReactJS codebase for the pharmacy site by incorporating client-requested features, elevating its functionality and user experience.
- · Hired to bring the Figma-designed online vaccination clinic to fruition, I built it using ReactJS and SCSS.

Professional Poker Player

Self

January 2006 - Present

• As a person who loves to use critical thinking and problem solving, poker became one of my favorite hobbies at a young age. After spending countless hours of independent research, I became a professional poker player and was able to comfortably pay my bills while maintaining my own schedule and mental health. As engaging and stimulating as professional poker is, I am more interested in using these skills in ways that help others and have tangible results of applications and products that better the world.

EDUCATION

Certified Web Developer

Bottega University \cdot Utah \cdot 2019

Manchester Community College

Manchester Community College • 2006

· Aug 2005 - Dec 2006

University of Vermont

University of Vermont • 2005

· Aug 2004 - May 2005

SKILLS

Relevant Skills

Willingness to learn, critical thinking, attitude,

adaptability, and empathy.

Javascript, ReactJS, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Redux Toolkit, RTK Query, Next.js, Node.js,

 $GraphQL, Redux, AWS, Python\ 3, CSS, HTML5, Git,$

SQL Databases, SCSS, Flexbox, CSS Grid, Redis, UML.

Design Tools: Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Heroku, Figma, AdobeXD.